Ing. Martin Kožený

Phone: (+420) 724 735 822

Email: martin.kozeny@gmail.com

Personal

Born on December 21, 1986.

Czech Republic Citizen.

Marital status: single.

Driving licence: yes (B).

Spoken languages: Czech - mothertongue, English - fluent, German - good, French - basic.

Profile

I have quite a lot experiences with programming in Java (both J2SE and server programming in J2EE) and recently started developing in JavaScript. I am also interested in other programming languages and using alternative programming techniques. I passed during my studies many courses related to artifical intelligence which is also object of my interest. In my current work I deal with J2EE technologies, databases and client side development.

Education

Java SE 7 Programmer I Certification, February 2014

Stanford University, Automata, January 2014

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne, Principles of Reactive Programming, January 2014

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne, Functional Programming Principles in Scala, December 2013

Stanford University, Introduction to Mathematical Thinking, November 2013

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne, Linear and Discrete Optimization, May 2013

Stanford University Compilers online course, July 2012.

Stanford University Game Theory online course, May 2012.

Ing. Computer science - software engineering, Czech Technical University in Prague, 2009–2012.

International exchange student of computer science, University of New Orleans, 2011.

CISCO Networks certificate, CCNAE 1, 2010.

Bc. Computer science, Czech Technical University in Prague, 2006–2009.

First Certificate in English (FCE), 2006.

Physics Olympiad – regional round: 2nd place 2004, 4th place 2006; national round 2006 – honorable mention.

Grammar school Dašická Pardubice, graduated with honor, 1998–2006.

Ing. Martin Kožený

Employment

Software developer at Oracle. December 2012–present.

Duties: Developing desktop applications based on NetBeans Platform, working on NetBeans IDE itself primarily on apisupport ant project type. Working on Application Builder Cloud Service (ABCS), which is tool for Oracle Cloud. This includes client side (JavaScript, KnockoutJS, Jasmine, Atmosphere) and server side (Java, Maven, JUnit, JGroups) development.

Software developer at Arbes Technologies, s.r.o. May 2012–November 2012.

Duties: Developing enterprise applications in Spring framework. Created own generic framework for CRUD operations.

Software developer at Ample cz s.r.o. November 2007–April 2012.

Duties: Working on enterprise applications for government and for private sector involving its designing, modeling and implementation. Experiences with databases including data gathering and data normalizing for datawarehouse.

Tourist guide at Kinský dal Borgo, a.s. 2004–2011.

Duties: Tourist guide at castle Kost in summer season.

Areas of expertise

Programming languages

Java (J2SE, J2EE)

Scala

C/C++

Smalltalk

Ruby

Lisp

Prolog

Haskell

Databases

SQL language

MS SQL Server

MS SQL Server Analysis

Mondrian

PostgreSQL Server

Oracle and also its PL/SQL extension

MySQL

Administration

Administration of Gnu/Linux

MS Windows

Mac OS

Application server Tomcat

JBoss

Apache

WebLogic

Ing. Martin Kožený

Tools

Web Development

JBoss Seam Javascript Eclipse

Spring Jasmine NetBeans

Ajax SinonJS Ant

CSS Knockout Maven

HTML 5 Oracle JET Karma

XHTML JQuery Grunt

Hibernate Atmosphere ETL graphs

UML 2.0 JGroups Visual Studio

Web Services Jakarta Struts Enterprise Architect, Astah

JUnit testing PHP CVS, SVN, Git

Other

Squander framework

LATEX

XML

DocBook